

# Yogender Kumar

#### Contact

Chirawa Jhunjhunu, India 333026

+91 7790915264

yogender3107@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/ yogender-kumar-816543127

Portfolio: https://yogender31 07.github.io/profile

# **Core Qualifications**

- NodeJs
- Javascript
- GraphQL
- Git
- Microservices
- React
- Typescript
- Postgress
- MongoDB
- MySQLElastic

# ACCOMPLISHMENT

- Me and my team received
   Alchemist Award for our hard work and solutions in 2018.
- Performer of the year 2021 by Cardekho.

# **Professional Summary**

I am proficient in collaborating with team members and remote clients to effectively conduct requirements gathering and optimize solutions as per the requirements. With 7+ years of experience, I would like to work in an organization where I can use all my skills for the holistic development of the organization and myself.

#### Experience

#### SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Noumena Global US | Apr 2022 - Current

This platform is for the entrepreneur to register their business with Noumea and do all short of activities like events, messages, payments etc. As a user he can create wallet payments and pay by card and many more.

During this time I have taken care of Responsibilities

- Integrated Third party api for the payment solution
- Dwolla integration for Bank and wallet payment solution
- Plaid integration for bank account verification
- Stripe integration for Card payment solution
- Charge bee Integration for subscription.
- Worked closely with other team members to identify and remove software bugs.

# SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Skuad Lab India Pvt. Ltd | Gurgaon, India, India | Apr 2020 - Apr 2022

This Platform was developed to design the hiring process for both Skuad and the companies that are looking for resources for their project. It maintains all the candidate's records including their resume details and the interview track. Further more we have included contracts and payment between vendors and clients.

During this time I have taken care of Responsibilities:

- · Enabled cookie based authentication
- Build an identity service for user to login and authenticate any service
- Also worked upon Google Analytics for tracking of User activities
- Created Contract with panda doc.

#### SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Appstreet Software Pvt. Ltd | Gurgaon, India | Jan 2019 - Apr 2020

Over here I have worked with client Cardekho. For them we have designed the system(Linex) for them to give loan to customer through credit line. Repayment of loan. We also make the system(connex) to resell the car through auctions.

# **Education**

Poornima Institute of Engineering And Technology Jaipur, RJ

B.Tech: Computer Science 05/2016

70% Graduated with Honors

Army Public School Jodhpur, RJ Certificate of Higher Education: Science 2011

Passed 12th with 77.4 %.

During this time I have taken care of Responsibilities:

- Managed transaction for the systema and maintaining ledger items
- Defined and developed core logic before starting any module
- Google based authentication
- Responsible for managing backend schema for different entity used
- $\bullet\,$  Responsible for business understanding and then implementing accordingly.

#### ASSOCIATE IT

Daffodil Software Pvt. Ltd | Hisar, India | Jul<br/> 2016 - Dec2018

I have worked upon the core Product of Daffodil. I worked with the Applane for Education Product team that manages all the activities for the student like attendance, results, PTM, Timetables etc

During this time I have taken care of Responsibilities:

- Responsible for managing backend Schema for different entities used
- Responsible for managing report cards and attendance of the students
- Defined and developed core logic before starting any module
- Google app engine for application monitoring